Eamon Grennan papers, 1964-2010
Emory University
- Writings by Grennan, 1962-2010, Series 2; Boxes 3 - 53; BV 1 - 3
  - Prose, 1964-2010, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 40 - 41; BV 1
    - "American Grain," review of Chief Joseph of Nez Perce by Robert Penn Warren, no date (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - "Casting a Cold Eye," review of Moral Tales by Giacomo Leopardi, translated by Patrick Creagh, published in The Irish Times, 1984 (Box 41, Folder 24)
    - "Golden Oldies," review of Elizabethan Lyrics edited by Norman Ault, no date (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - Quotes promoting works by other authors, no date (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - Review of Colonial Consequences: Essays in Irish Literature and Culture by John Wilson Foster, no date (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - Review of Lake Geneva by Gerald Dawe, published in The Irish Times, no date (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - Review of Life Monitor by Ciaran O'Driscoll and The Song the Oriole Sang by Philip McDonagh, 2010 (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - "Reviewer Reviewed," review of Troubled Thoughts Majestic Dreams by Dennis O'Driscoll, no date (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - "Shelf Life," review of Finders Keepers: Selected Prose, 1971-2001 by Seamus Heaney, no date (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - "Still Wayfaring," review of Robert Lowell: Collected Poems edited by Frank Bidart and David Gewanter, no date (Box 41, Folder 32)
    - "War Correspondent?" review of Poetry in the Wars by Edna Longley, no date (Box 41, Folder 33)
    - "Whimful Book," review of The Faber Book of Contemporary Irish Poetry edited by Paul Muldoon, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 34)
    - Short stories
    - "Allegro Ma Non Troppo" [Variant title: "Olive"], typescript draft, circa 1964 (Box 41, Folder 35)
    - "Plato's Ghost," typescript draft, circa 1964 (Box 41, Folder 36)
    - "A Row of Copper-Beeches," typescript draft, circa 1964 (Box 41, Folder 37)
    - "Spring Has Four Seasons," typescript drafts, circa 1964 (Box 41, Folder 38)
    - "A Sudden Sunny Wind: A Fantasy in One Act," typescript draft, circa 1964 (Box 41, Folder 39)
    - "Ten Stories: Anabasis," notes, circa 1964 (Box 41, Folder 40)
    - Student papers
    - "Ben Johnson and the Coming Muse: A Note on Three Lyrics" (Box 41, Folder 41)
    - "The Constant Sacrament: The Figure of the Poet in The Shepheardes Calendar," circa January 1966 (Box 41, Folder 42)
    - "The Crumbling Pageant: A View of Dryden's Odes" (Box 41, Folder 43)
    - "Figured Worlds: Some Aspects of Landscapes in Dryden and Pope," May 23, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 44)
    - "History and Historia: A Reading of Shakespeare's History Plays," doctoral dissertation, December 1972 (Box BV1, -)
    - "Iron Truths: Tennyson's Aesthetic Dilemma," December 1965 (Box 41, Folder 45)
    - "The Ladder of Civility: A Structural Pattern in Book Six of The Faerie Queen," December 1967-January 1968 (Box 41, Folder 46)
    - "Myth as Metaphor: Paradise Lost" (Box 41, Folder 47)
    - "The Preface to Ralegh's History of the World" (Box 41, Folder 48)
    - "Providence, Fortune, Art: The Search for Meaning in King Lear," dissertation chapter draft (Box 41, Folder 49)
    - "Rejection and Acceptance in Gulliver's Fourth Voyage," January 6, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 50)
    - "Sacramental and Secular: A Changing Mode of Literary Perception," January 18, 1968 (Box 41, Folder 51)
    - "Sidney and the Golden World: Some Aspects of Landscape," May 16, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 52)
    - "Some Critics of Byron: A Reading Report," cover page, May 9, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 53)
    - "Some Notes on Dickens" (Box 41, Folder 54)
    - "Some Notes on Two Novels of George Eliot" (Box 41, Folder 55)
  - Notebooks, circa 1960s-2010, Subseries 2.3; Boxes 42 - 47; BV 2 - 3
    The subseries consists of notebooks kept by Grennan from the 1960s-2006. It includes a few academic notebooks about the Renaissance that Grennan wrote while he was a student at Harvard in the late 1960s. The majority of the notebooks, however, contain poetry and other writings, as well as miscellaneous notes.
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - No date [1 of 4] (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - No date [2 of 4] (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - No date [3 of 4] (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - No date [4 of 4] (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - 1963-1965 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - 1964 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - 1964 December (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Circa late 1960s, primary sources from the Renaissance (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Circa late 1960s, Renaissance historiography (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Circa late 1960s, secondary works on humanism, art, etc. during the Renaissance (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - 1978 February-August (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - 1978 August 10-1980 January (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - 1980 January 10-1981 March 8 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - 1984 January-1984 September (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - 1984 October-1986 June (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - 1987 June 1-1988 May 2 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - 1988 May 29-1989 June 23 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - 1989 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - 1989 September-1990 June (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - 1990 June 4-1991 May 11 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - 1991 January-June (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - 1991 Summer (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - 1991 May 11-1992 March 6 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - 1991 November (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - 1992 May 28-June 13 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - 1992 June 14-1993 March 7 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - 1993 March-July 27 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - 1994 June 7-September 9 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - 1994 June 20-1996 May 31 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - 1995 June 9-September 19 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - 1995 September 20-1996 March 13 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - 1996 May 25-June 14 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - 1997 January 7-May 15 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - 1997 May 16-1998 June 16 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - 1998 June 17-1999 July 16 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - 2000 (Box BV2, Folder -)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - 2001 April 12-December 13 (Box BV3, Folder -)
    - 1999 July 21-2004 June 14 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - 2001 January 1-April 11 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - 2001 December 14-2002 January 12 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - 2006 June-2007 Summer (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - 2006 September 30-2008 August 9 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Notes, no date (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Notes, 1972-2006 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Lectures, poetry readings, and teaching filest, circa 1980s-2009, Subseries 2.4; Boxes 48 - 53
    The series consists of files relating to lectures and poetry readings given by Eamon Grennan, and classes and workshops taught by Grennan. Lecture files include notes and drafts, as well as supplementary material relating to the topic. These files document invited lectures given outside a classroom setting. Poetry reading files include information about the event, as well as the poems Grennan read. Teaching files may include syllabi, notes for lectures, reading assignments and research material. Some courses have been identified, however most files could not be tied to a single course offering and are instead arranged independently by subject.
    Arranged in alphabetical order by topic.
    - Lectures
    - Autobiography, no date (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Beckett, Samuel, untitled lecture, Poetry Society of America presents Samuel Beckett and Poetry, New York, New York, circa 2006 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Bishop, Elizabeth and Wallace Stevens, "'The Imperfect is our Paradise': Bishop and Stevens," no date (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Chaucer, Geoffrey, "Stained Glass: A Talk on Chaucer," no date (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Dickinson, Emily, "'Identity to Seek': The Selves of Emily," Branching Out: Poetry for the 21st Century, 2005 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Heaney, Seamus and "soul," untitled lecture, no date (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Irish-Americans, untitled lecture, The Cultural Voice of Irish New York, City University Graduate Center, New York, New York, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Irish history, untitled lecture, no date (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Irish love poetry, untitled lecture, no date (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Irish poetry, "Irish Stew: A Taste of What's Happened since Yeats," no date (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Kavanagh, Patrick, "Kavanagh's Hereafter: The Ins and Outs of It," Boston College, 2004 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Leopardi, Giacomo, "Leopardi in English," no date (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Lowell, Robert, "Sill Wayfaring," Poets on Poets, no date (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - McGahern, John, "'Only What Happens': Mulling over McGahern," no date (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Oedipus at Colonus, untitled lecture, no date (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Shakespeare, William, untitled lecture, no date (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Simmons, James, "Alive and Kicking," no date (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Stevens, Wallace, notes, no date (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Stevens, Wallace, "Thirteen Ways of Looking at a Poem by Stevens," and "'I Was of Three Minds': Notes Toward Reading Stevens," no date (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Tennyson, Alfred (Lord), "Keeping Faith: Some Thoughts on Tennyson's Music," Poets on Poets, 2001 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Translation, "The Ache of Translation," Boston University, no date (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Translation, untitled lecture, no date (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Translation in Irish literature, untitled lecture, no date (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Twelfth Night by William Shakespeare, "Sport Royal, Sex, Sweet Nothings: Some Thoughts on Twelfth Night," no date (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Whitman, Walt, untitled lecture, Walt Whitman Tribute Evening, Lannan Foundation, Santa Fe, New Mexico, February 11, 2009 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Wyatt, Thomas, "Driving to the Interior: Wyatt's Voice," no date (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Yeats, William Butler, "Yeats and Ireland: A Winding Star," no date (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Yeats, William Butler and Patrick Kavanaugh, "Yeats, Kavanaugh, and Others, a Talk," no date (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Zanzotto, Andrea, "Andrea Zanzotto: Stellar and Homely," Raiziss/DePalchi Book Prize, 2008 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Poetry readings
    - Poetry in the Branches, a joint program of Poets House and the New York Public Library, April 20, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Unidentified set lists, circa 1986 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Teaching files
    - Blank verse and free verse (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Course: The Craft of Poetry, Vassar College, circa 2002 [1 of 2] (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Course: The Craft of Poetry, Vassar College, circa 2002 [2 of 2] (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Course: Irish Poetry, Vassar College, no date (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Course: Literary Tour of Ireland, 1997 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Course: Lyric Poetry, introductory materials, no date (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Course: Modern Poetry, Vassar College, no date (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Course: The Oliver St. John Gogarty Society Celebration, 50th anniversary, field trip with Eamon Grennan, County Galway, Ireland, 2007 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Course: Verse: A Semester, no date (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Dickens, Charles (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Dickenson, Emily [1 of 2] (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Dickenson, Emily [2 of 2] (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Donne, John (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Essays on poetry (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Figurative language and the sonnet (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Forms (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Hardy, Thomas (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Heaney, Seamus, his influences (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Herbert, George (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Influence [Includes "In the Kitchen with Yeats" by Eamon Grennan] (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Joyce, James, poems (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Joyce, James, Ulysses (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Kavanaugh, Patrick (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Leopardi, Giacomo, samples of translators (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Line and sentence (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Mahon, Derek, circa 1991 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Meter and rhythm (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Painting (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Petrarch plus (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Poem drafts for classes [Includes "Station," "That Ocean," "Double Vision," and "Walk: Night Falling" by Eamon Grennan] (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Poets, 16th and 17th centuries (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Sestina (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Sound, diction and learning by heart (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Stanza, strophe, verse and paragraph (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Student papers about Grennan (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Syntax (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Teaching evaluations, 2003-2004 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Tennyson, Alfred (Lord) (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Translation (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Trevor, William, circa 1998-2001 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Workshop: Poetry writing workshop, Guggenheim Museum (?), no date (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Workshop: Potential poems to read (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Yeats, William Butler [1 of 2] (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Yeats, William Butler [2 of 2] (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Translations, circa 1995-2005, Subseries 2.5; Boxes 54 - 55
    The series contains poems and plays written by other authors and translated by Grennan. Of particular note are materials relating to Sophocles's Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger and published in 2005. Also present are Grennan's translations of poems by Giacomo Leopardi, Eugenio Montale, and others. The subseries also contains translations of Grennan's poems in French, as translated by Michèle Duclos.
    - Translations by Grennan of others' works
    - "Andreas," from the Vercelli Book, typescript and manuscript drafts [Includes editorial correspondence] [published in The Word Exchange: Anglo-Saxon Poems in Translation edited by Greg Delanty and Michael Matto] (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Jaccottet, Philippe, "A la lumière d'hiver" (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Leopardi, Giacomo, Leopardi: Selected Poems, editorial correspondence, September 13, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Leopard, Giacomo, Leopardi: Selected Poems, towards Leopardi: Selected Poems (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Leopardi, Giacomo, Leopardi: Selected Poems, typescript draft (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Leopardi, Giacomo, Leopardi: Selected Poems, typescript draft [Photocopy], March 30, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Leopardi, Giacomo, Leopardi: Selected Poems, typescript draft [Photocopy] [Includes editorial correspondence], April 15, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Leopardi, Giacomo, Leopardi: Selected Poems, typescript draft [Includes editorial correspondence], December 2, 1996 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Montale, Eugenio, various poems (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Montale, Eugenio, various poems, editorial correspondence (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Pavese, Cesare, "Verra la Morte," (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Sophocles, Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger, editorial correspondence (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Sophocles, Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger, manuscript draft, literal translation by Kitzinger [1 of 2] (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Sophocles, Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger, manuscript draft, literal translation by Kitzinger [2 of 2] (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Sophocles, Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger, manuscript draft (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Sophocles, Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger, manuscript and transcript draft (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Sophocles, Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger, notes (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Sophocles, Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger, reference material (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Sophocles, Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger, typescript draft incorporating suggestions by Peter B. and Alan S. (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Sophocles, Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger, typescript draft, third (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Sophocles, Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger, typescript draft, fourth (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Sophocles, Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger, typescript draft, fifth (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Sophocles, Oedipus at Colonus, translated by Grennan and Rachel Kitzinger, typescript draft, penultimate (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Translations by others of Grennan's poetry
    - Translations of Grennan's poems into French by Michèle Duclos [Includes editorial correspondence] (Box 55, Folder 10)
- Writings by others, 1969-2010, Series 3; Boxes 56 - 57; OP 1
  The series consists of literary manuscripts written by other authors and sent to or collected by Grennan from 1969-2010. The series includes writings by others about Grennan, including interviews, introductions of Grennan, and reviews of Grennan's works. The series also contains poetry and prose pieces by other authors such as Louis Asekoff, Seamus Heaney, Tom MacIntyre, and Desmond O'Grady, that were sent to or collected by Grennan.
  - Writings about Grennan
  - Anderson, Nathalie, introduction of Grennan, Swarthmore College, no date (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Anderson, Nathalie, introduction of Grennan, Swarthmore College, no date (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Bedient, Cal, introduction of Grennan, Pacific Design Center in Los Angles, March 4, 1997 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Cahill, Timothy, interview with Grennan, published in Writers Online, 1998 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Cording, Bob, introduction of Grennan, College of the Holy Cross, November 30, 2004 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Deppe, Ted, introduction of Grennan, Eastern Connecticut College, no date (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Hobbs, John, interview with Grennan, published in Irish Literary Supplement, fall 1998 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Jordan, Kieran, "Life that Harkens after Brightness: The Poetry of Eamon Grennan," senior thesis, May 1996 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Keane, Damien, introduction of Grennan, University of Pennsylvania, March 31, 2000 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - LeClair-Gates, Mary Ellen, "Painterly Poet: Eamon Grennan, Katonah Library," 1985 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Lennon, Joesph, introduction of Grennan, University of Connecticut, no date (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Maritime, [?], untitled essay on birds in Grennan's poetry [Includes correspondence], September 7, 1996 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Murphy, Kevin, introduction of Grennan, Syracuse University (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Murphy, Kevin, review of As If It Matters [Includes correspondence], July 17, 1992 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Quinn, Justin, interview with Grennan, published in Metre 9, Spring 2001 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Ross, David, review of What Light There Is and Other Poems, no date (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - Sadoff, Ira, review of Matter of Fact by Grennan, Elegy by Mary Jo Bang, and Backward Day by Stuart Dischell, no date (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Smith, Virginia, interview with Grennan, April 20, 1992 (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - Smucker, Mark, "Eamon Grennan and Nature," term paper [Includes correspondence], April 22, 1991 (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - Tillinghast, Richard, "Eamon Grennan: 'To Leave Something Bright and Upright Behind,'" review of What Light There Is and As If It Matters, no date (Box 56, Folder 20)
  - Wiseman, Martha, introduction of Grennan and Billy Collins, June 6, 1997 (Box 56, Folder 21)
  - Unidentified author, introduction of Grennan, no date (Box 56, Folder 22)
  - Unidentified author, introduction of Grennan [Includes correspondence], September 29, 2000 (Box 56, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified author, introduction of Grennan, Cornell University, October 21, 1999 (Box 56, Folder 24)
  - Unidentified author, introduction of Grennan, Greenwich Library, Greenwich, Connecticut, November 18, 1998 (Box 56, Folder 25)
  - Unidentified author, introduction of Grennan, Sunken Garden Poetry Festival, Hill-Stead Museum, Farmington, Connecticut, no date (Box 56, Folder 26)
  - Unidentified author, introduction of Grennan, University of St. Thomas, Minneapolis, Minnesota, no date (Box 56, Folder 27)
  - Unidentified author, "Letter to Eamon Grennan about his Three Poems," no date (Box 56, Folder 28)
  - Various authors, blurbs about Grennan's works (Box 56, Folder 29)
  - Other poetry and prose
  - [?], Shelia, "Country Galway," no date (Box 56, Folder 30)
  - Asekoff, Louis, "Annunciation," March 26, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 31)
  - Asekoff, Louis, "Babel," November 8, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 32)
  - Asekoff, Louis, "Black Spot, no date (Box 56, Folder 33)
  - Asekoff, Louis, "The Prisoner," 1986 (Box 56, Folder 34)
  - Asekoff, Louis, "Talking to the Ancestors," March 24, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 35)
  - Bell, Julian, Still Life and Other Poems, proof, 1987 (Box 56, Folder 36)
  - Boland, Eavan, "On the Discovery of New Territory," "The Flight of the Earls," and "Migration," no date (Box 56, Folder 37)
  - Brandes, Rand, "The Portrait of the Artists as Homanus Vulgaris," no date (Box 56, Folder 38)
  - Carelton, Sarah, "Beware of Bull," no date (Box 56, Folder 39)
  - Criegh [?], John Patrick, "Monday Morning" and "Elegy," no date (Box 56, Folder 40)
  - Gibson, Margaret, "The Choice," December 2006 (Box 56, Folder 41)
  - Goodman, Paul, "The Lordly Hudson," no date (Box 56, Folder 42)
  - Graves, Robert, "The Cool Web," no date (Box 56, Folder 43)
  - Hart, Henry, "A Gift of Warblers," no date (Box 56, Folder 44)
  - Heaney,Seamus, "Lanterns," manuscript, no date (Box 56, Folder 45)
  - Janvier, Ludovic, "Deux poems inèdits," published in Sites: The Journal of Twentieth-Century/Contemporary French Studies, October 29, 2010 (Box 56, Folder 46)
  - Kitzinger, Rachel [?], "Growing Older with Oedipus, no date (Box 56, Folder 47)
  - MacIntyre, Tom, "Aisling," no date (Box 56, Folder 48)
  - MacIntyre, Tom, "Connemara," no date (Box 56, Folder 49)
  - MacIntyre, Tom, "Drumlin Prayer," April 9, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 50)
  - MacIntyre, Tom, "Excursion to Emhain Macha" May 15, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 51)
  - MacIntyre, Tom, "Fèirín," no date (Box 56, Folder 52)
  - MacIntyre, Tom, "October Walk," no date (Box 56, Folder 53)
  - MacIntyre, Tom, "Return Visit," no date (Box 56, Folder 54)
  - O'Grady, Desmond, Bones, typescript draft, 1969 (Box 56, Folder 55)
  - O'Grady, Desmond, "A Poem for Grennan," illustrated scroll, 1969-1970 (Box OP1, Folder -)
  - O'Grady, Desmond, "Reading the Unpublished Manuscripts of Louis MacNeice at Kinsdale Harbour," 1965 (Box 56, Folder 56)
  - O'Grady, Desmond, "A Selection from Odes," 1969 (Box 56, Folder 57)
  - O'Grady, Desmond, unidentified poem fragment, January 1969 (Box 56, Folder 58)
  - Russell, Peter, "Devastation" [Includes correspondence], no date (Box 56, Folder 59)
  - Russell, Peter, "Late Winter Spring," March 5, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 60)
  - Russell, Peter, "Song," May 28, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 61)
  - Taylor Marilyn, "Oh Lord, How I'd Love to be Irish," no date (Box 56, Folder 62)
  - Unidentified author, "The Sea in Winter," 1977-1978 (Box 56, Folder 63)
  - Unidentified author, untitled essay, 1979 (Box 56, Folder 64)
  - Unidentified author, untitled poem fragment, no date (Box 56, Folder 65)
  - Unidentified author, untitled typescript including various poems, 1977 (Box 56, Folder 66)
  - Various authors, "Eleven Irish Poets," edited by Grennan, published in Verse Issue 6 [Includes editorial correspondence and poems by Seamus Heaney, Peter Fallon, Frank Ormsby, Medbh McGuckian, Derek Mahon, and others], 1986 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Various authors, Ploughshares, volume 6 number 1, edited by Grennan and Seamus Heaney [Includes poem by Desmond O'Grady], 1980 (Box 57, Folder 2)
- Diaries, 1962-2008, Series 4; Boxes 58 - 75